Hi Im Geeta, a beauty therapist and hairdresser from india.
Now let us say, the easily available products in the market are the face packs.
now these masks are very easy to get ready from the market and use at home.
Let us talk about the moisturizing mask.
The moisturizing name itself suggests that it moisturizes the skin and is meant for dry type of skin.
As dry skin has patchiness, dullness on the skin and dead cells on the skin.
So this mask gives moisture retention to the skin.
Apart from this, it also removes dry flakes from the skin and the fine lines.
In short it helps in the cell metabolism of this type of skin.
Now let us take Martha Clay masks.
These are great for the oily type of skin as this absorbs the excess oil from the skin without disturbing the moisture level of the skin which is very important in using any type of mask.
Now this also blurt the shiness from the oily skin apart from this it constrict the pores and also remove the dead skin cells from the skin.
Now let us come to the exfoliating mask.
Now the exfoliation action itself suggests that it removes the surface debris from the skin which means the dead layers of the skin are remove with the help of the exfoliating actions and this gives the skin in their difficult condition.
This mask are also helpful in enormous skin types as enormous skin also sometimes suffer from dullness and sometimes with blackheads.
Now comes the peel off mask which are great for any type of skin as they refresh the oily areas and nourish the dry skin